<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Equestria CLST.</title>
    <description>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.
</description>
    <link>https://giphouse.github.io/CLST-2020//</link>
    <atom:link href="https://giphouse.github.io/CLST-2020//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 05:47:45 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 05:47:45 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.6</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the CLST-2020 wiki!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here we describe how certain stuff should be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have a few pages. Below you find the git pipeline. We have a seperate page for doing pull requests.
See &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/GipHouse/CLST-2020/wiki/pull-requests&quot;&gt;Pull requests guidelines&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please see https://github.com/GipHouse/CLST-2020/wiki/Continious-integration-explained for reasons your CI failed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How to write tests &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/GipHouse/CLST-2020/wiki/Writing-unit-test&quot;&gt;https://github.com/GipHouse/CLST-2020/wiki/Writing-unit-test&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;git-pipeline&quot;&gt;GIT pipeline&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have one master branch. Everything must work on this branch. That is, ./manage.py runserver should not have any issues. Furthermore, the features should be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To start adding a feature do the following:
1) Start pulling master, to make sure you are up to date.
2) Make a new branch, call it featurebranch. &lt;strong&gt;Give it a descriptive name&lt;/strong&gt;. Also if needed write a short description in the branch what it exactly should do. 
Possible starts for branch names are&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;structure/&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;feature/&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;design/&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;refactor/&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Code some cool stuff in the branch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) When done, make sure to pull the master to be up to date as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) NEW!! Make sure you have black installed. This is our format tool. Do:
$poetry shell. 
Now make sure you are outside the git repo:&lt;br /&gt;
$ cd .. 
&lt;br /&gt;
Now you can check if your code is formatted nicely! Our CI will fail your branch if it does not pass it.&lt;br /&gt;
$ black –check CLST-2020&lt;br /&gt;
If fails, one can fix it automatically with:&lt;br /&gt;
$ black CLST-2020&lt;br /&gt;
This will reformat the full directory. One cal also specify one file instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) commit your branch.
7) Do a pull request on your branch, stating you wish to have it merged with master.
8) Ask someone to review your pull request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CI:
&lt;br /&gt;
We have several CI stuff integrated in our workflow. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the master we really wish to keep our badges in README working. That is, on the readme page you should see passing for all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DO NOT:&lt;/strong&gt;
keep everything locally. Its fine to commit to feature branches!
use one branch, other than master, for adding multiple features. 
Create unneeded branches. (Try to keep a minimal number of branches)
Commit to master (only via pull request)
break other peoples stuff, on master. That is, it is fine to modify code, but it should not &lt;em&gt;intentionally&lt;/em&gt; break other features. If you know it breaks something, discuss it first.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 05:15:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>https://giphouse.github.io/CLST-2020//jekyll/update/2020/06/03/home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://giphouse.github.io/CLST-2020//jekyll/update/2020/06/03/home.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Student readme</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;welcome-to-equestria&quot;&gt;Welcome to Equestria&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;your-online-language-toolset&quot;&gt;Your online language toolset&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;logging-in&quot;&gt;Logging In&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before You can begin using it, You will need to log in. To do this press the “Log in” button on the home page, or the user icon in the top right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/wikiImage/loginscreen.png&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will then be prompted with the log in screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/GipHouse/CLST-2020/blob/master/wikiImage/LoginFormScreenshot.png&quot; alt=&quot;LogIn Form&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This form also offers functionality to register with a new account using the “Sign up” button, as well as resetting Your password in case You forgot is using the “Forgotten password” button.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please note the requirements You have to fullfill when creating a new account as listed on the sign up page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;starting-your-first-project&quot;&gt;Starting Your First Project&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After logging in You should head over to the “Project Overview” page. This can be done by clicking the “Project overview” button, clicking the “Select Project” header in the navigation bar, or clicking the user icon and selecting the “My Projects” item.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/GipHouse/CLST-2020/blob/master/wikiImage/GoToProjectOverview.png&quot; alt=&quot;Go to overview&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note that You will not have the option “Site admin” in the dropdown menu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/GipHouse/CLST-2020/blob/master/wikiImage/ProjectCreateForm.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;Project create form&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the project creation form, enter a project name You have not used before, also make sure to only use alphanumerical character, i. e. [a-z, A-Z, 0-9] and select an according pipeline. Upon clicking “Create” You will be redirected to the “Upload  files” screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;uploading-files&quot;&gt;Uploading Files&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here You can upload the files You want to work with within the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/GipHouse/CLST-2020/blob/master/wikiImage/UploadFilesForm.png&quot; alt=&quot;Upload file form&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mucho Importante: For each audio-text-combination You will have to create a separate project!
You will need to upload both a text file and an audio file. Allowed file formats are .txt, .tg, .wav, or a zip archive containing the necessary files.
Both files should have the same filename (except for the extension .txt, .tg, and .wav). Otherwise, while it will let You click “Continue”, correct output is not guaranteed.
Once all files have been uploaded, click the “Continue” button to proceed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;forced-alignment&quot;&gt;Forced Alignment&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/GipHouse/CLST-2020/blob/master/wikiImage/FAPage.png&quot; alt=&quot;Upload file form&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After clicking the “Continue” button on the upload page, the forced alignment will automatically be run. It will show You the progress via console output on the right side and the current status on the left. Once it is done, click the “Continue” button.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;grapheen-to-phoneme&quot;&gt;Grapheen to Phoneme&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/GipHouse/CLST-2020/blob/master/wikiImage/G2PPage.png&quot; alt=&quot;grapheen to phoneme conversion&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This page works in very much the same way as Forced Alignment. Grapheen to phoneme will run automatically, once it is done, click the “Continue” button.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;check-dictionary&quot;&gt;Check Dictionary&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/GipHouse/CLST-2020/blob/master/wikiImage/CheckDictPage.png&quot; alt=&quot;Dictionary update form&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here You can add words to the dictionary that is used during forced alignment and rerun it. The current version of the dictionary will also be displayed here. If You are satisfied with the current version of the dictionary just click on “Continue to FA Overview”. Otherwise alter the content in the textfield above and click on “Update dictionary and rerun FA”, so that the Forced Alignment can be done with the new version of the dictionary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/GipHouse/CLST-2020/blob/master/wikiImage/Overview.png&quot; alt=&quot;Overview form&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the final page of the forced alignemnt pipeline. Here You can repeat any of the previous steps, download the results, and delete the project if You are done.
If the output does not match what You expected, You can go back to the check dictionary section to add words to it and rerun the forced alignment and grapheen to phoneem steps. You can also add more files via the upload fiels page.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://giphouse.github.io/CLST-2020//student/readme</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://giphouse.github.io/CLST-2020//student/readme</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How do I edit the address of an already existing CLAM server?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;to change the address of an already existing CLAM server, go to the admin page&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://giphouse.github.io/CLST-2020//2020/01/01/editAddressClam.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://giphouse.github.io/CLST-2020//2020/01/01/editAddressClam.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to add another language</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You can access the admininstrative section of equestria either by going to equestria.ru.nl/admin or clicking the “Site Admin” item in the dropdown menu of the user icon. Now, click the “add” button at Pipelines under Scripts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/GipHouse/CLST-2020/blob/master/wikiImage/AddLanguage.png&quot; alt=&quot;Adding a language&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here, you can name the new language and add the scripts by clicking the “add another script” button. A new window will open, which will look like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/GipHouse/CLST-2020/blob/master/wikiImage/AddLanguage2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Adding a language script&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can use the same information for both of the types of scripts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this window you can give a name to the script. It also requires a hostname. This could be a link to webservices-lst.science.ru.nl/&lt;newlanguage&gt;. You can add a description to the language to add clarification. There&#39;s also a Username and a Password field.&lt;/newlanguage&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The username should be: clst&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The password field should be left empty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After you’re done adding the information for the scripts, you click “save” and the window will close. 
Now, you can hit “save” in the “add pipeline” page and the new language is added.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://giphouse.github.io/CLST-2020//2020/01/01/addLanguage.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://giphouse.github.io/CLST-2020//2020/01/01/addLanguage.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Admin readme</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-admin-page&quot;&gt;The Admin Page&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-command-center-located-at-urladmin&quot;&gt;The command center located at url/admin&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-to-access&quot;&gt;How to Access&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can access the admininstrative section of equestria either by going to equestria.ru.nl/admin or clicking the “Site Admin” item in the dropdown menu of the user icon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/GipHouse/CLST-2020/blob/master/wikiImage/AdminOverview.png&quot; alt=&quot;Admin Page&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon reaching the admin site and having logged in You will be greating with an overview of all database models used within the server.
On the right side of the page You will see a log of recent activities of the site admins.
Please ignore user profiles, it has no real use and is an artifact of implementing personalization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;models&quot;&gt;Models&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Groups: Currently empty, no clue what it does PLEASE EDIT THIS&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Users: List of all users with detailed information&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tasks: Currently running server background tasks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Completed Tasks: Tasks that have been finished as well as additional information&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Projects: Projects created by users&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pipelines: Language pipelines used in projects&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Profiles: CLAM server profiles for G2P and FA&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Input templates: Templates used by profiles&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scripts: Connection to scripts for CLAM server&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Processes: Scripts that have been run and their status&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Parameters: Used for dynamic form generation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Choice parametes: Used for dynamically generated choice fields in forms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;usage&quot;&gt;Usage&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add instances to a model, press the “+ Add” button. You will be prompted by a form that contains all necessary fields to create a new instance of that model. Fill these in and press “Save” to finalize the creation process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To look at or alter instances of a model, click either the model name, or the “Change” button of that model. You will be directed to a complete list of all instances of that model.
While You will not be able to search the entries with a regular search bar in all models, it is possible to apply filters based on the properties of the model on the right side of the page.
Click one of the instances to see all their attributes. In this screen you can also change the values of the fields and update the instance. Instances can also be delted in this screen.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://giphouse.github.io/CLST-2020//2020/01/01/AdminPage.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://giphouse.github.io/CLST-2020//2020/01/01/AdminPage.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
